Patrik Billgert Högalidsgatan 46A 117 30, Stockholm, Sweden Email / LinkedIn / Portfolio



PROFILE

Versatile, open-minded and self-propelled developer that highly values a great user experience. Ten years experience in developing applications for the App Store. Been working with many different types of companies ranging from local startups to global brands.

Passionate about infrastructure and design. I enjoy working with automation, optimization, experimentation, scalability, architecture & new technologies. Always learning and continuously trying to enforce simplicity when programming & designing apps.

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Main

Swift, Objective-C, Xcode, Cocoa Touch, UIKit, SwiftUI, Swift Concurrency, WatchKit, WidgetKit, Core Data, AVFoundation, Core Location, SceneKit, RxSwift, CocoaPods, Swift Package Manager, Git, CI/CD, Xcode Cloud, GitHub Actions, Fastlane

Secondary

C#, Javascript, Unity3D, React.js

EXPERIENCE

iOS Developer Bokadirekt

MAY. 2023 - Present, Stockholm

Freelance Developer KODA KODA

APR. 2018 - Present, Stockholm

App development consultant working with companies like:

- Deloitte Digital (helped their client Electrolux)
- Deedster (startup fighting climate change)
- Dashl (helped define, design and develop the prototype)

Lead iOS Developer BRUCE

OCT. 2019 - DEC. 2022, Stockholm

Even if developing the app was my main responsibility, I also played a big role in designing the ui/ux, leading the product development, structuring how we managed projects and improving our ways of working.

Lead iOS Developer Doberman

JAN. 2019 - OCT. 2019, Stockholm & New York

Aida Calculus - the world's first AI enabled Calculus tutor by Pearson. Huge project spanning across three different timezones (New York, Denver and Stockholm). With over 40 people involved, I was part of the product team and led the development of the iOS application from start. Spent three months in the US.

iOS Developer BBH Stockholm

AUG. 2015 - APR. 2018, Stockholm & New York

Formerly Monterosa. Responsible for developing, publishing and maintaining apps while exploring new technologies. Working in teams consisting of producers, creatives, designers, testers and developers. Clients included Rebtel, Volvo & TUI among others. Spent three months with the New York office.

iOS Developer Frontcell

MAR. 2013 - AUG. 2015, Stockholm

Frontcell is a mobile agency where I worked with clients mainly focusing on Objective-C and Swift. Worked with clients like Litago, Fabege & Swedish Church.

Bartender Various bars

AUG. 2007 - AUG. 2012, Stockholm, Copenhagen & London

After high school I worked as a cocktail bartender where I developed my social skills and attention to detail.

EDUCATION

Application Development Malmö Yrkeshögskola

AUG. 2012 - MAR. 2013, Malmö

Studied Objective-C and created my first app called Happy Stream which was a radio streaming service that made it into the music top 20 on App Store. Did my internship at Frontcell which I later joined full-time.

Graphic Communication Nordic Technical Institute

SEP. 2004 - JUN. 2007, Stockholm

RECOMMENDATIONS

Joe Fraga

Engineering Manager at Doberman, New York

"Patrik is an excellent iOS developer. His ability to move fast and focus and to step back and look at the whole picture is remarkable. Working both in person and remotely, collaboration was always fluid, smart and humble."

Erik Agrell

CTO at BBH Stockholm, Stockholm

"With his high technical skills within mobile development combined with his easy going personality, he always was a great asset to the team. Patriks most prominent personality trait is his dedication and strive to always make the best possible product no matter what it takes. Something that was always highly appreciated among the clients he worked with."